<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GridMine – kyc</title>
    <link>/tags/kyc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kyc on GridMine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="/tags/kyc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Onboarding and Fraud Remodelling - Financial Services</title>
      <link>/docs/solutions/004-onboarding-and-fraud-remodelling-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/solutions/004-onboarding-and-fraud-remodelling-finance/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;onboarding-and-fraud-remodelling&#34;&gt;Onboarding and Fraud Remodelling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leverage an industry proven onboarding and Know Your Customer (KYC) ontology and fine-tune it to your corporate compliance policies. Ensure manual processing, existing triggers and information sources are tied together by a unified and harmonized process supporting front-office and compliance simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;problem-statement&#34;&gt;Problem statement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many financial service providers struggle with the complexity and inefficiency of their client onboarding and recurring KYC monitoring practice. And many have issues, when it comes to Anti-Money Laundering (AML), source of funds and transaction monitoring compliance. The front-office staff often tries to cut corners and the compliance staff is overwhelmed with the number of cases and follow-ups that are required from them. Disintegrated and high-maintenance systems and processes are the usual status quo, with little budget and energy to change from due to the inherent risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;target-market--industries&#34;&gt;Target market / Industries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use case is primarily applicable to the industries that are exposed to frauds and where fraud tracking and prevention is needed. The financial services industry benefiting most from this use-case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We combine the domain knowledge of what is really required by law and regulation with the opportunity to automate many aspects of the background screening and adverse media monitoring. By integrating the robustness of process of global players and the lean and mean approach FinTech startups take, we usually are able to raise quality while reducing effort. Creating a centralized compliance officer workbench that is integrated with both front-office systems as well as risk-management and compliance tools, we are able to iteratively improve the situation by synchronizing the learning of the models and predictions with the feedback from compliance experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution included:
-Integrated Compliance Officer Workbench&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onboarding &amp;amp; Compliance Ontology configuration &amp;amp; subsequent ontology matching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration of existing screening &amp;amp; trigger sources with learning / improvement loops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation of standard cases and pre-filling of high-probability issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aggregation of findings, reporting, alerting &amp;amp; compliance action notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stakeholders&#34;&gt;Stakeholders&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compliance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-elements-assets-and-deliverables&#34;&gt;Data elements, Assets and Deliverables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an Input from the client, the following items were used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Existing client onboarding / KYC policies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KYC/AML/onboarding management cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client‘s contracts, positions &amp;amp; transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assets &amp;amp; Artefacts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client risk attributes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Historic client behavior information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deliverables included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compliance &amp;amp; KYC Ontology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compliance Officer Workbench&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use case specific orchestration flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;impact-and-benefits&#34;&gt;Impact and benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decreased compliance team by 30% from 18 down to 12 Fuull-Time Employees by automating standard case load. Increased compliance quality and decreased client case resolution time by eliminating aspects not required by current jurisdictional scope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;testimonials&#34;&gt;Testimonials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is a compliance expert‘s dream come true. Before I never had an oversight of where I or my team where standing. Now we can actually support our client facing colleagues.&amp;rdquo;
— Mr. XXX YYY, Title, Company ZZZ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tags--keywords&#34;&gt;Tags / Keywords&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#fraud #fraudremodelling #compliance #kyc #financialservices #bank&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Onboarding and Fraud Remodelling - General</title>
      <link>/docs/solutions/004-onboarding-and-fraud-remodelling-general/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/solutions/004-onboarding-and-fraud-remodelling-general/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;onboarding-and-fraud-remodelling&#34;&gt;Onboarding and Fraud Remodelling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leverage an industry proven onboarding and Know Your Customer (KYC) ontology and fine-tune it to your corporate compliance policies. Ensure manual processing, existing triggers and information sources are tied together by a unified and harmonized process supporting sales and compliance simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;problem-statement&#34;&gt;Problem statement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many service providers struggle with the complexity and inefficiency of their client onboarding and recurring KYC monitoring practice. And many have issues, when it comes to various types of monitoring of client’s activities. The front-office staff often tries to cut corners and the compliance staff is overwhelmed with the number of cases and follow-ups that are required from them. Disintegrated and high-maintenance systems and processes are the usual status quo, with little budget and energy to change from due to the inherent risk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;target-market--industries&#34;&gt;Target market / Industries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use case is primarily applicable to the industries that are exposed to frauds and where fraud tracking and prevention is needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We combine the domain knowledge of what is really required by law and regulation with the opportunity to automate many aspects of the background screening and adverse media monitoring. By integrating the robustness of process of global players and the lean and mean approach, we usually are able to raise quality while reducing effort. Creating a centralized compliance officer workbench that is integrated with both front-office systems as well as risk-management and compliance tools, we are able to iteratively improve the situation by synchronizing the learning of the models and predictions with the feedback from compliance experts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution included:
-Integrated Compliance Officer Workbench&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onboarding &amp;amp; Compliance Ontology configuration &amp;amp; subsequent ontology matching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration of existing screening &amp;amp; trigger sources with learning / improvement loops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automation of standard cases and pre-filling of high-probability issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aggregation of findings, reporting, alerting &amp;amp; compliance action notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stakeholders&#34;&gt;Stakeholders&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compliance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-elements-assets-and-deliverables&#34;&gt;Data elements, Assets and Deliverables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an Input from the client, the following items were used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Existing client onboarding / KYC policies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;KYC / onboarding management cases&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client‘s contracts, positions &amp;amp; transactions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assets &amp;amp; Artefacts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client risk attributes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Historic client behavior information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deliverables included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compliance &amp;amp; KYC Ontology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compliance Officer Workbench&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use case specific orchestration flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tags--keywords&#34;&gt;Tags / Keywords&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#fraud #fraudremodelling #frauddetection #fraudtracking #compliance #kyc&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docs: Prospecting 360 Degree</title>
      <link>/docs/solutions/001-prospect-360-finance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/solutions/001-prospect-360-finance/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;h2 id=&#34;prospect-360&#34;&gt;Prospect 360°&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many strategic prospects the preparation of possible offers and establishment of a real relationship either involves great effort or lacks structure and focus. The Prospect 360° use case augments traditional advisor intelligence with automation to improve this original dilemma.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 2 Problem statement --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;problem-statement&#34;&gt;Problem statement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hunting for new important clients usually is driven by referrals and the search for an “ideal event“ to introduce a product or service. Existing client relationships are usually screened manually and approached directly to request an introduction, prior to offering any services. Monitoring the market and a prospect’s connections can be cumbersome and is error prone – either introductions are awkward or they do not focus on a specific and urgent need. Hence the success and conversion rates seem hard to plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 3 Target markets --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;target-market--industries&#34;&gt;Target market / Industries&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This use case is traditionally applicable to such industries where the customer engagement and acquisition process is long and costs per customer are high:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Insurance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;General Business Services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- 4 Solution description --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We introduce the idea of “soft onboarding”. Instead of selling hard to a new prospect, we start to engage them with tailored and relevant pieces of information or advice free of charge. We do, however, tempt this prospect to embrace little initial pieces of an onboarding-like process, extending the period we are allowed to profile the needs and preferences of the client and the related social graph. Turning a prospect into an interested party and then increasing the levels of engagement of the period of up to six months allows for a more natural and client-driven advisory experience, that is shifting from a “product push” towards a “client pull”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The solution included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration of disparate news &amp;amp; event information sources (licensed &amp;amp; public origins)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provisioning of select RM &amp;amp; client data points to understand social graphs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Word parsing of text-based inputs (e.g. news articles and liquidity event streams)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Onboarding &amp;amp; Sales Ontology matching&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identification of possible liquidity events, new referral paths &amp;amp; sales topics of interest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aggregation of findings, reporting, notifications and organizational routing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideally inclusion of reinforcement learning (via RM, client &amp;amp; assistant feedback loops)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;example-use-case-agent-cascade&#34;&gt;Example Use Case Agent Cascade&lt;/h5&gt;






&lt;p&gt; 
            &lt;img src=&#34;/streamzero/images/solutions/uc_001_2021.png&#34; style=&#34;border:2px solid #fff;
            box-shadow: 10px 10px 5px #ccc;
            -moz-box-shadow: 10px 10px 5px #ccc;
            -webkit-box-shadow: 10px 10px 5px #ccc;
            -khtml-box-shadow: 10px 10px 5px #ccc;&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- 5 Stakeholders --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;stakeholders&#34;&gt;Stakeholders&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relationship Management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sales&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marketing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- 6 Inputs, tools and deliverables --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-elements-assets-and-deliverables&#34;&gt;Data elements, Assets and Deliverables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an Input from the client, the following items were used:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sales organization setup (desks / books)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Client to Client / Client to Company graphs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;capabilities-utilized&#34;&gt;Capabilities utilized:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unstructured Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semantic Harmonization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NLP&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personalization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;assets--artefacts&#34;&gt;Assets &amp;amp; Artefacts:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial Product Ontology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analytical CRM Models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;the-deliverables-included&#34;&gt;The deliverables included:&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sales &amp;amp; Onboarding Ontology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use case specific orchestration flow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integration with many info sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- 7 Implementation results --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;impact-and-benefits&#34;&gt;Impact and benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategic client team originally covered 200 prospects manually. Introducing Prospect 360° allowed to double that number while reducing the time-to-close by 35% — from more than 12 to an average of about 7 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use-case implementation resulted in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;+8%&lt;/strong&gt; growth of corporate loan book&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;+22%&lt;/strong&gt; reduction on credit defaults&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 8 Testimonials --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;testimonials&#34;&gt;Testimonials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I feel a lot more as a real advisor. I can be helpful and feel informed. And I still can make my own judgments of what is relevant for my personal relationship to existing clients and new referrals. I learn as the system learns.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Mr. Pius Brändli, Managing Director, Credit Suisse&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- 9 Tags / Keywords --&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;tags--keywords&#34;&gt;Tags / Keywords&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#kyc, #knowyourcustomer, #finance, #financialservices, #onboarding, #prospecting, #prospect360&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
